You could even win a reward!
We don't have any other leads,
so we should at least try
using the Stratumlord coins.
It's a perfect fit.
One problem.
The Menagerie of Fools has four coins.
Origin, Dead, Clearflow, Labyrinth.
And we're packing three.
Clearflow, Scorching, and lastly, Dark.
We have seven coins total, but two are
clear flow and we're missing Dog Mountain.
Well, still worth a try.
Looks like it won't let us through
without the Dog Mountain coin.
Hold on a minute.
An old box?
Director Bear said we
should only open this
when we had finally made
it to the inner depths.
Jackpot.
Is that the doggy coin?
That Sly Bear came
through for us. Sure did.
I've been told his old team were the
only ones to ever defeat Dog Mountain,
so my hopes were sky high.
He's the biggest and best bear I know!
He's that sexy!
Thanks for the plug device, pal.
You're a real MVP, dude.
On the outside, I'm just a big metal box,
but inside I've still got a human soul!
In this new world of wonders,
I travel to and fro on the back
of my super strong partner Lamas!
The name's Boxxo! Hello there!
That means yes, by the way!
And there you be With all 12
Except that peculiar I got
my ear You get my ear I
found it I can't wait Sit here
That's her Don't Voke Don't
show a crash Stay with Alan
My feelings the wrong way I can
come I find it I can't help Um,
let's open this door No connection
The moment
Before we go,
let's make sure we're on the same
page about the wishes we want granted.
Our little family only has a single wish.
To remove decay, Kai's negative blessing.
Nothing more.
But if we can get another,
I want a hot girlfriend!
Don't be so selfish, I'll
take one too, extra hot!
What about you?
My dearest wish has already come true, so
I'll happily yield mine to everyone else.
If there's a spare, I'll
take a castle of boots.
I don't need anything either.
Just let me eat until I'm about
to burst it, we'll call it even.
Pity had a wish.
But mine has already come true as well.
Well, I do have a wish.
In truth, it is something
I must win for myself.
I don't need a thing.
Well, Lamas?
Nothing for myself.
There is something I want,
but it's not for me to ask.
Guess I'm up to bat.
I know what I want.
I went to beek you ma-in
again. Yay! Thank you.
But captain goes first.
Cap goes first.
I'm putting my non-existent foot down.
You sure?
But there's a chance
we'll only get one wish.
There are up-er-de-int-ins.
I can wait for it.
That's a good point.
There are plenty of other
dungeons in the world.
So if you don't end up getting
your wish granted here,
that just means we get to go
and conquer some other dungeon.
And I'll be with you every
step of the way. Same here.
These straps aren't budging.
Where Master goes, I follow.
Are we there yet?
Afraid not.
We've been walking a
while, but it's so dark.
Hard to tell how big this place is.
That's about what I expected.
Now the lights are on but nobody's home.
You have done well to
make it here, travelers.
As a reward for reaching
the lowest stratum,
I shall grant you whatever
wish your heart desires. Whoa.
He's really gonna do the thing.
But first, I can sense that one of you.
Your standing before me is more than
capable of threatening my dungeon.
I assume you're referring to me.
I used to work for the Netherlord.
Listen well.
The Netherlord seeks to seize my dungeon
constructed from the sacred tree.
Fool, it's already
stolen most of my power.
Who's that old guy?
Heed my warning!
Talking purple's a real pain, so
how's about I just give it a rest?
Slap my bum and call me Sally!
Never in a million years did I think some
dumb kiddos would show
up and storm my dungeon.
I was about to go on break, too!
He's giving jaded office worker who hates
his life and copes by trolling in forums.
Not how I pictured the Dungeon Master.
I take it you're the one in charge
of this nasty little dungeon?
Well, that's one way to put it.
I'm the guy those in the
know call the Dungeon Master.
Back in the day,
they used to throw around words like
genius and visionary, but I digress.
I'm forgetting my manners.
And look at this table.
Go on, you can rest your keisters.
I'm sure you've got a boatload
of questions to ask me.
I'm an open book, so if
it's in my power to answer?
I don't mind giving you folks the exposition
dump, but let's get some snacks going.
Hello there.
Look at that.
It's my lucky day.
I've always been curious about
these here thingamabobbers.
As a stalwart vending machine, I mean,
I'm the head honcho of feeding folks.
Plus, taking ownership of edibles keeps
my pals safe from any drink tampering.
All right, let's hear what
questions you've got cooking.
Okay, so what's the deal with
dungeons and dungeon masters?
Getting right to it.
Dungeons are basically just
vanglorious works of art.
Created by ancient wizards to
show off our ancient wizardry!
because why not?
Or you could think of them
as recreational facilities.
The dungeon master is the
individual who made the dungeon.
Ancient wizards making dungeon art?
I don't know, seems like I
would have heard about it.
We wizards died out, for reasons.
As a result, history has forgotten
us and the world with it, I'm afraid.
Old wizards made these dungeons,
to brag about how cool they
were for making dungeons?
Are you being serious?
Never would have guessed
this world had its
own equivalent to modern game developers.
Is it true that for
reaching the lowest level,
you'll grant any wish our hearts desire?
Yep, the rumors are true.
How many wishes do we get?
You can technically make
as many as you want.
There's no maximum.
However, that doesn't mean you
can have anything and everything.
Granting a wish consumes an amount of mana
that's proportional to its wow factor.
Which means your wishes
are only limited by the
amount of mana contained
within this dungeon of mine.
Do you have the power to remove
my son's negative blessing? I do.
Do it.
I wish for you to free him from his curse.
Better untwist those britches.
I'm not done explaining
all the fine print yet.
Let's say you wish for a bunch of
silver gold and jewels in obscene piles.
I fork over my entire personal treasure
trove without using a single lick of mana.
That said,
removing a negative blessing is gonna eat
up a huge slice of this
dungeon's mana pie. Gotcha.
Then I have one last question.
Can you cure Kai's decay and
also turn Boxxo human again?
I can do it by the skin of my teeth.
But after those two,
I'll be completely out of mana and
unable to grant you any further wishes.
Wait, am I about to rejoin humanity?
Yes, this is for you, Boxxo.
You deserve every happiness, Master.
Congratulations, Boxxo.
Now I can make my wish
with a clear conscience.
It's happening!
One skin for the teeth.
I had my hopes up, but I never
really thought it would happen.
Pinch me, Lamas! Be warned,
if I do grant those wishes of yours,
this dungeon will collapse
and crush everything within.
Wouldn't we die?
Damn, we were this close to
making Boxxo human again.
If the dungeon collapses, it'll flatten
my friends into tragic tortillas.
That price is too steep to
make my selfish wish come true.
Unless...
Ma-enk-you-er-witch-k-a-k-a-k-ang-o-la-ent-er.
You want me to start by
removing the boy's negative
blessing Then you'll
evacuate all your little
friends And make the journey
back here by yourself
Letting you make your wish
guilt-free He's either
amazing at guessing or
he can read my mind like
Kikuyu It seems the Netherlord
has sealed the dungeon
exit just to be a jerk
But I can temporarily
open it again Then we've
got a plan Good thinking,
Boxo Hello there
In that case, I'll go ahead and
remove this boy's curse of decay
The pain is gone.
It's a miracle.
The Scorch's blessing of
decay is gone for good.
He'll never again have to suffer the
torment of feeling his flesh rotting away.
I am in your debt.
At long last, you're free.
There's nothing binding you to me.
I may not need your magic,
but I choose to stay with you.
I hope you don't mind.
I've been waiting for this moment.
So, that's where you were hiding.
Sorry, what gift?
I swear I didn't know about any of this.
Even I never expected this
plan to work out so well!
The fruits of victory are sweet.
Granting such a wish drained
a great deal of his power.
I can now finally extinguish
his life with relative ease.
That's a foul trick!
You can't scoot to such depths just
to get past my anti-monster barrier.
I've sent more of your
power away, Dungeon Master.
Your precious dungeon is
practically in the palm of my hand.
You used me to sneak your way in here?
You're my property.
Why shouldn't I make use of you?
Don't you dare objectify her! Zorin,
given your loyalty,
I'm willing to make an exception
and allow you to return to my side.
The old me would have been more than
happy to go crawling back to you.
But I'm not that girl anymore.
Now I have something
that's far more dear to me.
Sentimental fool. Audrey!
Oh, you erased it with eye breach.
Can't let you kill off a young lady
who might join our family one day.
What's our next move?
We've got the captain's
eye breach and my barrier.
Paired with their gimmicks, we
might actually stand a chance.
It would be amusing to continue this
battle, but I have already achieved my goal.
Let's begin a different game.
The kind of magic has you there
feels like a four on the Richter.
It's freaking them out because
they've never felt an earthquake.
If you keep this up, you'll
cause this dungeon to collapse.
That's exactly what I intend to do.
I got what I came for,
which means I have absolutely no
reason to preserve this place.
I'll move the monsters to the surface
and watch as the humans suffer and die.
What's wrong with you?
Can't you just get a hobby?
Monsters solely exist to
inflict pain and spread sorrow.
The Demon Lord has strayed from this path.
It's pathetic.
I look forward to seeing which comes
first, the collapse or your demise.
He vanished?
Without killing us off?
Listen, I'm going to conjure a
transfer circle for you folks.
It will transport you back to
the Clearflow Lake Stratum.
Go back there and take everyone with you.
Escape the dungeon while you can.
With my remaining power,
I'll release the door leading
to the surface so you can leave.
I don't know how much
longer my power will last,
so it wouldn't be a bad idea to
hot-foot it out of here, got it?
This old man wizard is going
to sacrifice himself for us?
Hey, Boxo, sorry I couldn't grant
your wish and make you a real boy.
You must be devastated.
Ike, H for Ike again.
What a fascinating fella.
I'll try to keep the dungeon from
collapsing for as long as I can,
though I can't make any promises.
What about you, Dungeon Master?
Don't worry, that pretty little head.
This is how it works.
Whenever a dungeon is conquered,
the Dungeon Master grants the
wishes, then vanishes away.
I've lived longer than anyone should.
Didn't expect it to end like this, but at
the very least, it's worth a good laugh.
Say, Poxo,
I know I wasn't able to grant that wish
of yours, but here, a parting gift.
May a promising future
await the brave hunters
who I had the honor of
crossing paths with today.
They who conquered the
dungeon of the Sacred Tree.
Congratulations on your triumph.
Thank you for joining my
dungeon to the very end.
It was a real home and a house.
I never could have imagined
it would come to this.
We need to evacuate everyone
to the Origin Stratum now.
We've got to get them out of this dungeon.
I understand.
Big boss!
We got backup!
Hey, it's the Might Lady!
Lamas, Voxo, our top priority is
securing the door leading outside.
You got it.
Come on, Bear.
Excuse us.
Thank you very much.
Lamas, Director Bear, there's trouble.
What's the issue?
Gross monsters are swarming the village.
There's no choice.
We'll have to evacuate in small groups.
I'll turn you all into charcoal
and use you to warm our clipsies!
Silver King 14! Eat!
Freaking out's a waste of energy.
You've got to keep the calm, cool, and
collected vibes going to yours, too.
Uranu's got game.
We've almost got everyone out.
Methinks our battle montage
will buy us just enough time.
Dang, I wish I had some wood to knock on.
I seem to have underestimated
your team's tenacity.
The big bad.
I find your efforts quite riveting.
So, I'll briefly release
my hold on the door.
It's always so late.
The greatest joy in hunting
comes from cornering your prey.
and watching them squirm.
You're a nasty piece of work, mister.
So, what do we do now?
Please go.
I knew she'd understand.
Now, time for a form change.
Behold the biggest
vending machine in Japan.
Hmm, you dare to defy me,
magic item known as Boxlow?
Even though we're both well aware, you
cannot maintain that form for long.
That's a fact.
Using my barrier in this form
is blowing through my points.
Good thing I'm loaded now.
I've got points to spare.
Thanks to him!
The least I can do is fill your coffers.
Please add this gift to your point total.
The Dungeon Master gifted me
his entire treasure trove.
You wouldn't believe how
many zeroes I'm packing!
I'll keep this barrier up until
every last person gets away!
Hey, Voxo!
What do you think you're doing?
You're gonna get left
behind if you don't stop!
She's not gonna like this,
but it's the only way!
Leave the int to my indigo! I refuse!
I'm not leaving your side!
If you're staying, I am too!
Voxo has a better chance of coming back
safely if we're not around to distract him.
That's it, right? Yes!
I can't leave him! We're a team!
Don't be silly.
You know we'd only be in the way.
So put your faith in him, and
let's go. I don't wanna. I can't.
Don't be sad, Lamas.
Dying's not on my Dead
list, but winning is.
And that's why, no matter what,
I won't let you in the barrier.
Let me in.
I look forward to serving you again.
I give up.
I won't be selfish anymore.
But you'd better come
back to me in one piece.
Hello there.
If you die, I'll kill you.
I'll help you.
Even if you get buried, I promise
I'll come and dig you out.
All you've got to do is wait for me.
You're sacrificing yourself
to save your friends?
Your determination amuses me. Thank you.
I encourage you to consider something.
I have been lurking within the
confines of a bracer upon Saurim's arm.
It is an extension of me and
still very much attached to her.
What's he all about?
I'll show you why this
matters. What's happening?
Voxo and the Netherlord, what
the heck? Didn't we leave?
That jerk forced Solreen to use
her blessing of transference.
Damn you, bony bullies.
Now then, Kerioyl,
I suggest you use your blessing of
Eyebreach to remove that barrier.
Unless you want to watch your
son and future daughter-in-laws.
Let's burst open.
Dad, don't give in.
What a brave son you have.
Now make your choice.
Refuse my command and you both die.
Or erase the barrier
and I'll let you live.
There's no time to lose.
That's why I removed the barrier myself.
Well done.
Let us delight in watching as this
permusing magic item is destroyed.
Don't sweat it, Cap.
I made the call, and that's that.
979 damage.
I'm so sorry.
I'm so...
979 damage.
Durability has been decreased by 979.
You are no longer able to
sustain your current form.
Revenue to original model.
LAMAS
It's a story that I'm going to meet you?
Make a look, make a rendezvous!
Make you wait for me!
I'll be waiting for you!
I'll feel you like you're feeling!
Oh, it's not just a good thing!
I'm gonna be a TV show!
I'm not a good thing!
I don't want to say anything.
I look forward to serving you again.